A Guide to the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Yucca Mountain Research Collection TD898.12.N3 U85
University of Nevada, Reno. DeLaMare Science & Engineering Library
U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Yucca Mountain Research Collection
1957-2006
TD898.12.N3 U85
University of Nevada, Reno. DeLaMare Science & Engineering Library
120 cubic feet (256 boxes)
Administrative History
The U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) was formed as part of the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974. The NRC is responsible for regulating nuclear fuel cycle and waste management activities; as well as commercial, industrial, medical, and academic uses of nuclear energy.
Scope and Contents
During its time as a Nuclear Regulatory Commission depository, the University of Nevada, Reno collected thousands of documents related to the potential nuclear waste repository at Yucca Mountain, Nevada. The collection includes U.S. Government issued reports and contractor work related to the proposed site, as well as email communications, letters, research articles, books, educational pamphlets, maps, and other materials related to Yucca Mountain nuclear waste repository activities. Please see associated U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Yucca Mountain Research Collection LibGuide for more information about this collection, along with links to other related resources. This collection is housed at the DeLaMare Science & Engineering Library, basement floor.
Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Materials must be used on-site. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
As part of the NRC’s Code of Federal Regulations, Local Public Document Rooms (LPDRs) containing information about NRC activities and research were established near civilian nuclear power reactor sites and nuclear waste sites around the country. The Yucca Mountain Research Collection was acquired by the UNR during its time as a LPDR for the NRC beginning in 1989.
Arrangement
Kept in original order
U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission; Yucca Mountain Project (U.S.); United States. Department of Energy. Yucca Mountain Project Office; Nevada Nuclear Waste Storage Investigation Project (U.S.); United States. Department of Energy. Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. Office of Policy and Outreach; United States. Department of Energy; Yucca Mountain Site Characterization Project (U.S.); Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory; Los Alamos National Laboratory; Sandia National Laboratories; United States. Department of Energy. Nevada Operations Office. Waste Management Project Office; Radioactive waste disposal in the ground--Nevada--Yucca Mountain; Radioactive waste sites—Nevada--Yucca Mountain--Safety Measures; Radioactive waste repositories -- Nevada -- Yucca Mountain; Radioactive wastes--Transportation; Radioactive wastes--Storage; Radioactive wastes—Packaging; Radioactive waste disposal; Geology -- Nevada -- Yucca Mountain; Spent reactor fuels; Rock mechanics—Research; Shoshoni Indians; Paiute Indians; Volcanic ash, tuff, etc; Yucca Mountain (Nev.); Nevada Test Site (Nev.); Nye County (Nev.); Las Vegas (Nev.); Caliente (Nev.); Death Valley (Calif. and Nev.); Hanford Site (Wash.); Tooele County (Utah); Inyo County (Calif.); Idaho National Laboratory Region (Idaho)
- U.S. Department of Energy. "Yucca Mountain environmental assessment references: Full texts of selected references in microfiche cited in the Environmental Assessment: Yucca Mountain Site, Nevada Research and Development Area, Nevada." E 1.68/2:0073. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- TRW Environmental Safety Systems, Inc. "Mined geologic disposal system advanced conceptual design report." Volume II of IV repository, B00000000-01717-5705-00027 REV 00. Introduction-section 6. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- TRW Environmental Safety Systems, Inc. "Mined geologic disposal system advanced conceptual design report." Volume II of IV repository, B00000000-01717-5705-00027 REV 00. Section 7-9. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- TRW Environmental Safety Systems, Inc. "Mined geologic disposal system advanced conceptual design report." Volume II of IV repository, B00000000-01717-5705-00027 REV 00. Section 10-appendix F. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Yucca Mountain Project Office, U. S. Department of Energy. "Yucca Mountain Project site atlas." VAX Quarterly, #30, YMP/88-21. Introduction-ch. 4.1.7. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Yucca Mountain Project Office, U. S. Department of Energy. "Yucca Mountain Project site atlas." VAX Quarterly, #30, YMP/88-21. Ch. 4.1.8-4.1.14 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Yucca Mountain Project Office, U. S. Department of Energy. "Yucca Mountain Project site atlas." VAX Quarterly, #30, YMP/88-21. Ch. 4.1.15-4.1.31. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Yucca Mountain Project Office, U. S. Department of Energy. "Yucca Mountain Project site atlas." VAX Quarterly, #30, YMP/88-21. Ch. 4.1.32-4.2.9. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Los Alamos National Laboratory. "Volcanism synthesis report." Milestone 3781. Part I of II: Preface - ch. 2. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Los Alamos National Laboratory. "Volcanism synthesis report." Milestone 3781. Part I of II: Chapters 3-4. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Los Alamos National Laboratory. "Volcanism synthesis report." Milestone 3781. Part II of II: Chapter 5. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Los Alamos National Laboratory. "Volcanism synthesis report." Milestone 3781. Part II of II: Chapter 6. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Gupta, S.K., Cole, C.R., Kincaid, C.T. et al. "Coupled fluid, energy, and solute transport (CFEST) model: Formulation and user's manual." Office of Nuclear Waste Isolation, Battelle Memorial Institute. BMI/ONWI-660. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- TRW Environmental Safety Systems, Inc. "Catalog of planned boreholes for surface-based testing site characterization activities." BAA000000-01717-3300-00002 REV00. Introduction-p. 132. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- TRW Environmental Safety Systems, Inc. "Catalog of planned boreholes for surface-based testing site characterization activities." BAA000000-01717-3300-00002 REV00. Page 133-end. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Smith, E.I., Feuerbach, D., Naumann, T. et al. "Regional importance of post-6 M.Y. old volcanism in the Southern Great Basin, progress reports 1988-1989." Center for Volcanic Studies, Department of Geoscience. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Raney, R. "Simplified geologic map of Yucca Mountain in the vicinity of the perimeter drift and associated map overlays." U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Mines, Western Field Operations Center. NRC FIN D1018. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Sinnock, S., Fernandez, J.A. and Twenhofel, W.S. "Attributes and associated favorability graphs for the NNWSI area-to-location screening activity." Sandia National Laboratories. SAND82-0838. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Cook, G. "Yucca Mountain project update: University of Nevada, Reno seminar series." U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management, Yucca Mountain Site Characterization Project. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Gertz, C. "Project overview, presented to American Chemical Society." U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management, Yucca Mountain Site Characterization Project. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Younker, J. "Geological studies for site characterization, presented to Nevada Mining Association." Science Applications International Corporation and U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management, Yucca Mountain Project. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- U.S. Department of Energy, Yucca Mountain Site Characterization Office. "Environmental impact statement for a proposed repository at Yucca Mountain, Nevada: Summary of public scoping comments related to the environmental impact statement for a geologic repository." (Box 6, Folder 7)
- U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. "Managing the nation's nuclear waste: Factsheet series. [3 copies]." (Box 6, Folder 8)
- U.S. Department of Energy, Yucca Mountain Site Characterization Project. "Why are scientists studying Yucca Mountain?" DOE/RW-0395P. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- U.S Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. "OCRWM Backgrounder [newsletters]." (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Nevada Nuclear Waste Project Office. "Nevada nuclear waste factsheets." (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Nevada Nuclear Waste Project Office. "Nevada nuclear waste newsletters." (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Nevada Nuclear Waste Project Office. "Nevada Nuclear Waste Project Office bulletins." (Box 6, Folder 13)
- U.S Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. "[Yucca Mountain Project newsletters]." (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Citizens Against Nuclear Waste in Nevada. "[Newsletters]." (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Nevada Agency for Nuclear Projects, Nuclear Waste Project Office. "Nevada nuclear waste news [newsletters]." (Box 6, Folder 16)
- U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. "OCRWM Bulletins." (Box 6, Folder 17)
- U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management. "OCRWM Bulletins." (Box 6, Folder 18)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Introduction to chapter 4.2. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Chapter 4.3-4.5. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Chapter 4.6 to chapter 4.11. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Chapter 4.6 to chapter 4.11. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Chapter 7.0 to chapter 8. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Chapter 9. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- U.S. Geological Survey. "Seismotectonic framework and characterization of faulting at Yucca Mountain, Nevada." Chapter 10.0 to chapter 11. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Conference of Radiation Control Program Directors, Inc. "Directory of state agencies involved with the transportation of radioactive material, with notes on their statutory authority and regulations: Information as of September 1992." (Box 9, Folder 1)
- College of Engineering, University of Nevada - Reno. "The statewide radioactive materials transportation plan, phase II." (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Andrews, R.W., Dale, T.F. and McNeish, J.A. "Total system performance assessment - 1993: An evaluation of the potential Yucca Mountain repository." INTERA, Inc. B00000000-01717-2200-00099 Revision 01. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. "American trucking associations v. United States Environmental Protection Agency." (Box 9, Folder 4)
- American Indian Writers Subgroup Consolidated Group of Tribes and Organizations. "American Indian perspectives on the Yucca Mountain site characterization project and the repository environmental impact statement." (Box 9, Folder 5)
- American Ecology Corporation. "1998 news releases: Nevada acceptance makes American Ecology first U.S. firm to build, operate, successfully close radioactive waste facility." From AE News. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- American Cancer Society. "Cancer facts and figures - 1998." (Box 9, Folder 7)
- ACGIH Worldwide. "1999 TLVs and BEIs." (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Association of American Railroads. "Railroad facts, 1996 edition." (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Bland, J. "Maps showing minority and low-income census block groups in Nevada and greater Las Vegas." Regional Studies Department, U.S. Department of Energy. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Benson, L.V. and McKinley, P.W. "United States Department of the Interior geological survey: Chemical composition of ground water in the Yucca Mountain area, Nevada, 1971-1984." U.S. Geological Survey, U.S. Department of the Interior, in cooperation with the Nevada Operations Office, U.S. Department of Energy. OFR-85-484. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Bechtel Nevada Environmental Sciences Division. "Ecological monitoring and compliance program fiscal year 1997 report." (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Bauer, D.J., Foster, B.J., Joyner, J.D. and Swanson, R.A. "Water resources data Nevada water year 1995: U.S. Geological Survey water-data report." NV-95-1. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Barrett, L. "Program briefing for the U.S. Chamber of Commerce Energy and Natural Resources Committee, November 9, 1998." Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management, U.S. Department of Energy. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- "Technical position on tectonic models in the assessment of performance of high-level radioactive waste repositories - draft." (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Bredehoeft, J.D. "Response of the ground-water system at Yucca Mountain to an earthquake: An elastic continuum model." U.S. Geological Survey. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Nuclear Waste Project Office. "Why Nevada is opposed to Yucca Mountain." (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Nork, W.E. "Hydrologic support criteria for the safety of plowshare program industrial projects." Revision no. 2, PALTR-1229-184. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Brager, H.R., Rawlins, J.A., Schulz, W.W. et al. "CURE: A commercial high-level waste management alternative." Westinghouse Hanford Company and Pacific Northwest Laboratory. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- "[Misc. nuclear waste newsletters]." (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Raney, R. "Possible effects of surface and underground mining proximal to a closed high-level radioactive waste repository at Yucca Mountain, Nye County, Nevada." U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Mines. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- U.S. Department of Energy. "An introduction: Nevada nuclear waste storage investigations project." (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Mehas, T.C. "[Documents related to the final DAAG meeting. Letter to Weimer, B., Nevada Bureau of Mines and Geology, with attachments]." Fallout Records Centralization Project, Environmental Sciences Department. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- U.S. NRC Local Public Document Room Program. "LPDR update." (Box 10, Folder 15)
- U.S. Department of Energy. "Managing the nation's nuclear waste." (Box 10, Folder 16)
- "The Yucca Mountain debate status - April, 1993." (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Agency for Nuclear Projects Nuclear Waste Project Office. "[Misc. memorandums]." (Box 10, Folder 18)
- U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. "[Misc. memorandums]." (Box 10, Folder 19)
- T-Rex Transportation Resource Exchange Center. "National transportation information resource inventory 1998." (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. "Notice of application[s] filed with the commission." (Box 10, Folder 21)
- U.S. Department of Energy. "Why Yucca Mountain?" (Box 10, Folder 22)
- U.S. Department of Energy. "The path forward: A national repository at Yucca Mountain." (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Blanton, J.O. III. "Nevada test site flood inundation study: Part of the U.S. Geological Survey flood potential and debris hazard study Yucca Mountain site for United States Department of Energy Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management." Sedimentation Section, Surface Water Branch, Earth Sciences Division, United States Department of Interior, Bureau of Reclamation. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Bureau of Land Management, Las Vegas District Office. "Final environmental statement proposed domestic livestock grazing management program for the Caliente Area." Introduction to p. 8-80. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Land Management, Las Vegas District Office. "Final environmental statement proposed domestic livestock grazing management program for the Caliente Area." pp. 8-81 to 12-9. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District Office. "Draft management plan and environmental impact statement for the Shoshone-Eureka resource area, Nevada." INT DEIS 83-40. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Land Management. "Visual resource inventory, BLM manual handbook." U.S. Department of the Interior. 8410-1. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Bureau of Land Management, Nevada State Office. "U.S. Department of the Interior Bureau of Land Management right of way reservation." N-47748. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District, Tonopah Research Area. "Proposed Tonopah resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." TOC through 6-4. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District, Tonopah Research Area. "Proposed Tonopah resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." Appendices. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District, Tonopah Research Area. "Proposed Tonopah resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." Wilderness status maps. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Bureau of Land Management, Stateline Resource Area Office, Las Vegas, Nevada. "Draft stateline resource management plan and environmental impact statement." Vol. I introduction - ch. 2. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Bureau of Land Management, Stateline Resource Area Office, Las Vegas, Nevada. "Draft stateline resource management plan and environmental impact statement." Vol. I ch. 3-6. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Land Management, Stateline Resource Area Office, Las Vegas, Nevada. "Draft stateline resource management plan and environmental impact statement." Vol. II. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Bureau of Land Management, Las Vegas District Office. "Right-of-way reservation renewed." N-48602. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District Office. "Cortez Pipeline gold deposit final environmental impact statement - Volume 1. Cooperating agencies: Nevada Division of Wildlife." Introduction - ch. 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District Office. "Cortez Pipeline gold deposit final environmental impact statement - Volume 1. Cooperating agencies: Nevada Division of Wildlife." Ch. 3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District Office. "Cortez Pipeline gold deposit final environmental impact statement - Volume 1. Cooperating agencies: Nevada Division of Wildlife." Ch. 4-5 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District Office. "Cortez Pipeline gold deposit final environmental impact statement - Volume 1. Cooperating agencies: Nevada Division of Wildlife." Ch. 6 - appendices (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Land Management. "Executive summary for Proposed Las Vegas resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Bureau of Land Management. "Proposed Las Vegas resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." Vol. I. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Land Management. "Proposed Las Vegas resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." Vol. II: Appendices, glossary, references. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Bureau of Land Management. "Proposed Las Vegas resource management plan and final environmental impact statement." Vol. II maps. (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Land Management, Ely Field Office. "Proposed Caliente management framework plan final amendment and environmental impact statement for the management of desert tortoise habitat." (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Bureau of Land Management, Battle Mountain District. "Pipeline infiltration project environmental assessment." NV063-EA98-062 N64-93-001P (98-1A). (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Labor Statistics. "Safety and health statistics, Table 1. Incidence rates of nonfatal occupational injuries and illnesses by selected industries and case types, 1997." (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory in collaboration with The United States Geological Survey. "The site-scale unsaturated zone model of Yucca Mountain, Nevada, for the viability assessment." Introduction - ch. 15 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory in collaboration with The United States Geological Survey. "The site-scale unsaturated zone model of Yucca Mountain, Nevada, for the viability assessment." Ch. 16 - appendices. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Bostic, R.E., Kane, R.L., Kipfer, K.M. and Johnson, A.W. "Water resources data Nevada water year 1996: U.S. Geological Survey water-data report." NV-96-1. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Bonner, L.J., Elliot, P.E., Etchemendy, L.P. and Swartwood, J.R. "Water resources data Nevada water year 1997: U.S. Geological Survey water-data report." NV-97-1. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Brattstrom, B.H., and Bondello, M.C. "Effects of off-road vehicle noise on desert vertebrates." From Environmental effects of off-road vehicles. R.H. Webb and H.G. Wilshire, eds. (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Brown-Buntin Associates, Inc. "Background noise analysis, proposed Yucca Mountain nuclear depository Nye County Nevada." 97-215. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Bureau of Transportation Statistics. "Bureau of Transportation Statistics pocket guide to transportation." (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Bureau of Transportation Statistics. "DHIM section 1 - motor fuel." (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Bureau of Transportation Statistics. "National transportation statistics 1998 (NTS)." (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Buchanan, C.C. "Final biological opinion for reinitiation of formal consultation for Yucca Mountain site characterization studies." United States Department of the Interior, Fish and Wildlife Service, Nevada State Office. (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Buchanan, C.C. "Final biological opinion for reinitiation of formal consultation for Yucca Mountain site characterization studies." United States Department of the Interior, Fish and Wildlife Service, Nevada State Office. (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Buck, P. and Powers, C.D. "Nevada work instruction archaeological survey. Instructions NWI-ARCH-01 through -08." Civilian Radioactive Waste Management System, Management & Operating Contractor. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Bullard, K.L. "Nevada test site probably maximum flood study part of U.S. Geological Survey flood potential and debris hazard study Yucca Mountain site for U.S. Department of Energy Office of Civilian Radioactive Waste Management." Flood Section, Surface Water Branch, Earth Sciences Division, U.S. Bureau of Reclamation. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Buqo, T.S. "Baseline water supply and demand evaluation of southern Nye County, Nevada." Nye County Nuclear Waste Repository Office. (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Buqo, T.S. "Nye County perspective: Potential impacts associated with the long-term presence of a nuclear repository at Yucca Mountain, Nye County, Nevada: Water Resources Evaluation." (Box 18, Folder 11)
- U.S. Department of Commerce Economics and Statistics Administration Bureau of the Census. "1990 CPH-1-1 1990 census of population and housing summary population and housing characteristics United States." (Box 18, Folder 12)
- U.S. Department of Commerce National Technical Information Service. "Statistical abstract of the United States 1995 - The national data book." Preface - section 9. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- U.S. Department of Commerce National Technical Information Service. "Statistical abstract of the United States 1995 - The national data book." Section 10-26. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- U.S. Department of Commerce National Technical Information Service. "Statistical abstract of the United States 1995 - The national data book." Section 27 - index. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Economics and Statistics Administration and the Bureau of the Census. "Statistical Abstract of the United States 1997." (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Bureau of the Census. "1990 U.S. Census data [selected counties in Nevada: Clark, Elko, Esmeralda, Lander, Lincoln, and Nye]." (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Bury, R.B. and Germano, D.J. eds. "Biology of North American tortoises." U.S. Department of the Interior National Biological Survey. (Box 20, Folder 3)
- U.S. Supreme Court. "Cappaert v. United States, 426 U.S. 128 (1976), Cappaert et al. v. United States et al., No. 74-1107, argued January 12 1976, Decided June 7, 1976." (Box 20, Folder 4)